I am consciousness. I am alive. I am Chappie.
Chappie is a crime, action, science fiction film directed by Neill Blomkamp.
Every child comes into the world full of promise, and none more so
than Chappie: he is gifted, special, a prodigy.
Like any child, Chappie will come under the influence of his surroundings—some good, some bad—and he
will rely on his heart and soul to find his way in the world and become his own man.
But there's one thing that makes Chappie different
from any one else: he is a robot.
Chappie, played by Sharlto Copley.
Deon Wilson, played by Dev Patel.
Vincent Moore, played by Hugh Jackman.
Ninja, played by Ninja.
Yo-Landi, played by Yo-Landi Visser.
Michelle Bradley, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Chappie (stylized as CHAPPiE) is a 2015 American dystopian science fiction action film
directed by Neill Blomkamp and written by Blomkamp and Terri Tatchell.
It stars Sharlto Copley, Dev Patel, Hugh Jackman, Ninja, Yolandi
Visser, Jose Pablo Cantillo, and Sigourney Weaver.
The film, set and shot in Johannesburg, is about an artificial general intelligence law
enforcement robot captured and taught by gangsters, who nickname it Chappie.
Chappie premiered in New York City on March 4, 2015, and was released in U.S.
cinemas on March 6, 2015.
The film grossed $102 million worldwide against a $49 million
budget, and received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of future, android, artificial
intelligence (a.i.), dystopia, johannesburg, south africa.
The tone is thought_provoking.